<mod>
	<name>Closed Loop Ecology</name>
	<description>
		<![CDATA[Realistic carbon and nitrogen cycles for Space Haven.

Vanilla's life-support economy has three structural breaks:
- Composting biomass loses 87% of its mass to the accounting void
- Carbon is mineable but gated at Mining skill 7 (peer with Noble Metals)
- Chemicals → Fertilizer can only be made from Rot, which requires corpses

Peaceful playthroughs can't close the food loop without trading.

This mod ships five surgical patches:

1. Carbon mining skill 7 → 2 (matches Base Metals); Raw Chemicals 6 → 3.
   Carbonaceous chondrite asteroids become early-game accessible.

2. Composter carbon retention ×6 (1 biomass → 0.10 carbon, matches real
   biochar yields of 30-70%).

3. CO2 scrubber rebalanced to the exact mathematical inverse of the
   carbon burner. The C ↔ CO2 round-trip is now mass-conservative —
   no more free-carbon exploit from looping burner + scrubber.

4. New recipe — Industrial Chemicals Synthesis (interactive at the
   existing Chemical Refinery): 1 Carbon + 3 Water → 3 Chemicals.
   Real-world analog: Fischer-Tropsch synthesis. Closes the fertilizer
   cycle without combat dependency. Conditional "produce if storage < X"
   condition works because outputs are item-only.

5. New recipe — Biomass Pyrolysis (interactive at Chemical Refinery):
   2 Biomass → 1 Carbon. Real-world analog: industrial pyrolysis /
   charcoal production. Bypasses the lossy composter for high-throughput
   carbon refining.

Gas byproducts (oxygen from electrolysis, CO2 from pyrolysis) are
intentionally not modeled — they would break the conditional UI on
interactive recipes. Reserved for a future Pyrolysis Reactor station
that can host both the interactive recipe and its non-interactive
gas-vent on its own (without polluting vanilla stations).

After install, a peaceful 5-crew ship can run an indefinite food
cycle on the carbon they mine + the biomass they compost. Water
remains the primary bottleneck (ice mining), as in vanilla.]]>
	</description>
	<minimumLoaderVersion>0.12.1</minimumLoaderVersion>
	<version>0.2.0</version>
	<author>mingc</author>
	<modid>7700002</modid>
	<config></config>
</mod>
