<mod>
	<name>Closed Loop Ecology</name>
	<description>
		<![CDATA[Realistic carbon, water, and nitrogen cycles for Space Haven.

Vanilla's life-support economy has three structural breaks:
- Composting biomass loses 87% of its mass to the accounting void
- Carbon is mineable but gated at Mining skill 7 (peer with Noble Metals)
- Chemicals → Fertilizer can only be made from Rot, which requires corpses

Peaceful playthroughs can't close the food loop without trading.

This mod ships six surgical patches:

1. Carbon mining skill 7 → 2 (matches Base Metals); Raw Chemicals 6 → 3.
   Carbonaceous chondrite asteroids become early-game accessible.

2. Composter carbon retention ×6 (1 biomass → 0.10 carbon, matches real
   biochar yields of 30-70%).

3. CO2 scrubber rebalanced to the exact mathematical inverse of the
   carbon burner. The C ↔ CO2 round-trip is now mass-conservative —
   no more free-carbon exploit from looping burner + scrubber.

4. New recipe — Industrial Chemicals Synthesis (interactive at the
   existing Chemical Refinery): 1 Carbon + 3 Water → 3 Chemicals
   + 2 Oxygen Tanks. The tanks auto-vent to atmospheric O2 at any
   Life Support station. Real-world analog: Fischer-Tropsch synthesis
   plus water electrolysis. Closes the fertilizer cycle without
   combat dependency.

5. New recipe — Biomass Pyrolysis (interactive at Chemical Refinery):
   2 Biomass → 1 Carbon + 1 Char Residue. Residue auto-vents to CO2
   at the CO2 Scrubber. Real-world analog: industrial pyrolysis /
   charcoal production. Bypasses the lossy composter for high-
   throughput carbon refining.

6. Two-stage gas-byproduct pattern: gas outputs are bridged through
   transient inventory items (Oxygen Tank, Char Residue) so the
   interactive "produce if storage < X" condition keeps working on
   the crew-operated recipes, while the actual atmospheric release
   happens via non-interactive vents at appropriate life-support
   stations.

After install, a peaceful 5-crew ship can run an indefinite food
cycle on the carbon they mine + the biomass they compost. Water
remains the primary bottleneck (ice mining), as in vanilla.]]>
	</description>
	<minimumLoaderVersion>0.12.1</minimumLoaderVersion>
	<version>0.2.0</version>
	<author>mingc</author>
	<modid>7700002</modid>
	<config></config>
</mod>
